Guide to the Flower of the Dragon records, 1961-1981
Flower of the Dragon records, 1961-1981
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Flower of the Dragon Records, 1961-1981
7020
Flower of the Dragon Inc.
1.4 cubic ft.
Clippings, photographs, illustrations, audiotapes, manuscripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Various materials describing the Flower of the Dragon organization.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Flower of the Dragon was a community group concerned with Vietnam War veterans based in Santa Rosa, California.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Clippings about the organization; broadside; publications, mostly United States government; materials from anti-war groups; tape of radio program; reports; article; scrapbook; and photographs, slides, and negatives of unidentified Vietnam scenes.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Flower of the Dragon Inc.; Vietnam War Veterans Archives.
Subjects:
Soldiers.; Veterans.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975 -- Protest Movements.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975 -- Veterans.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- John W. Caknipe, Jr., 1973-1979; Reports and articles on vocational rehabilitation, drug abuse, and other programs for veterans. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- John W. Caknipe, Jr. Dissertation, 1978; "A Factor Analysis of the Metropolitan Detroit Area Vietnam Veteran: The Post Vietnam Veteran Syndrome." (Box 1, Folder 2)
- CHD proposal, 1974-1976; Grant application to the Campaign for Human Development to develop a consortium of self-help organizations for veterans in Northern California, articles of incorporation for Flower of the Dragon, and correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Mike Crawford, letter about a court action., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- James Donahue, ca. 1976; "The 5th Special Forces Mobile Guerilla Force Research Project Proposal" (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Flower of the Dragon, 1976; CETA proposal (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Flower of the Dragon, 1976-1979; Clippings (Box 1, Folder 7)
- History of the Veterans Service Center, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Incarcerated Veterans Project, 1979; National Council of Churches - papers, reports, grant proposal information packet (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Incarcerated Veterans Project, 1980-1981; "Vietnam Book Report Newsletter," Vietnam War Newsletter (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Incarcerated Veterans Project, 1980-1981; Louisiana State Penitentiary publication "National Vietnam Veterans Review" (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Incarcerated Veterans Project, 1978-1981; Miscellaneous reports and publications (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Incarcerated Veterans Project, 1979; Information for testimony before Senate Committee on Veterans Affairs (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Indochina Peace Campaign, publications, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Indochina Resource Center, Publications, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- National Association of Concerned Veterans, 1978; Testimony before U.S. Senate Committee on Governmental Affairs (Box 1, Folder 16)
- National Council for Universal and Unconditional Amnesty - Newsletter and petition, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Newspapers, 1973-1980; Firebaseamerica, Indochina Bulletin, Pogrom (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Orphans Airlift - Lists, schedules, form letters, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Pamphlets, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Jim Pechin, Operation Outreach - Documents for planning conference, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Pro-Veterans Center - Newsletters and report, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Reports and Papers, 1968-1980; Reminiscences, paper on veterans magazine article about movie, art exhibit description, annual report of DMZ (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Riverside Political Prisoners Defense Committee pamphlets and typescript report, ca. 1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Scrapbook, 1979-1980; Photocopies of clippings and articles, pamphlets, magazine, photograph (from the "media" scrapbook) (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Southeast Asia Chronicle, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Union of Vietnamese in the U. S. Newsletter, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- U. S. Government publications, 1961-1980; Refugee orientation handbook, country study, study of former POW's, President's speech. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- U. S. House of Representatives, 1980; Subcommittee on Medical Facilities and Benefits. Testimony from various organizations. (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Veterans Guidance and Counseling - UCLA Extension manual, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Vietnam veterans organizations - current (1) mailing lists, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Vietnam veterans organizations - current (2) mailing lists, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Vietnam veterans organizations - old mailing lists sent by Peter Salerno (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Scrapbook "Media" Clippings about veterans, 1975 (Box 2)
- Cassette tape, Oct. 8, 1979; "The Vietnam War Veteran" KPFA, San Francisco (Box 2)
- Photographs, Unidentified scenes of Vietnam, black and white, color. (Box 2)
- Negatives (Box 2)
- Slides of Vietnam, "Mike Roberts Color Productions Scenic Slides" sets 1-10 (Box 2)
- Vietnamese publications, 1967-1973; The N.F.L., Spirit of the Land (Cuban photos of Vietnam), Vietnam (magazine), Flower of the Dragon broadside (Box 2)